<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Kshitij Grover</title>
    <link>http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Kshitij Grover</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Newcomb&#39;s Paradox</title>
      <link>http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/newcomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/newcomb/</guid>
      <description>Newcomb&amp;rsquo;s paradox is interesting because the philosophical community is split on it almost evenly. [1]
I just want to introduce the problem here, and not make my own argument. In particular, I want to see what you think after reading the problem setup. I will detail very basic arguments, though.
Suppose you&amp;rsquo;re walking in the forest towards a small hut. Inside this hut, there is a wizard who can predict your actions with impeccable accuracy and has set up a game for you to play with two boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication at Caltech</title>
      <link>http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/communication-caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kshitijgrover.com/blog/communication-caltech/</guid>
      <description>As a graduating senior, it can sometimes be hard to have an unbiased perspective of institute policy; this is a time of transition perhaps from a sense of frustration over the 4-year curriculum’s perceived shortcomings to a more rose-tinted retrospective view. Despite this, there remains one important piece missing from Caltech as it prepares undergraduates for the “real world”[1] : teaching communication well.
The motto of our institute is “The truth shall make you free”, and certainly we represent it by advancing science and engineering through our labs and centers everyday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>